Professional and personal papers of Edwin Wolf 2nd LCP.EW2
Library Company of Philadelphia
- III. Scholarship, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
  - IIIa. Talks and Publications, Bulk, 1960-1988; 1895-1990
    - Issue of The Penn Charter Magazine, volume XL, number 352; including a piece by Edwin, "First-hand Impressions of the Pyramids", 1926 February (Item 5)
    - Issue of The Penn Charter Magazine, volume XL, number 356; including a piece by Edwin, "Bablyon", 1926 June 15 (Item 6)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XVIII, number 5, 1927 November (Item 7)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XVIII, number 6, 1927 December (Item 8)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 7, 1928 February (Item 9)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 8, 1928 April (Item 10)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 9, 1928 June (Item 11)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 10, 1928 July (Item 12)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 11, 1928 November (Item 13)
    - Issue of Bedales Chronicle, volume XIX, number 12, 1928 December (Item 14)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 1, number 3, 1954 October (Item 15)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 2, number 3, 1955 September (Item 16)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 3, number 2, 1956 June (Item 17)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 3, number 3, 1956 September (Item 18)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 3, number 4, 1956 December (Item 19)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 4, number 2, 1957 June (Item 20)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 4, number 3, 1957 September (Item 21)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 5, number, 1958 June (Item 22)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 5, number 3, 1958 September (Item 23)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 5, number 4, 1958 December (Item 24)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 6, number 2, 1959 June (Item 25)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 6, number 3, 1959 September (Item 26)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 6, number 4, 1959 December (Item 27)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 7, number 2, 1960 June (Item 28)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 9, number 2, 1962 June (Item 29)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 9, number 4, 1962 December (Item 30)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 10, number 2, 1963 March (Item 31)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 10, number 2A, 1963 June (Item 32)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 11, number 2, 1964 June (Item 33)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 11, number 4, 1964 December (Item 34)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 12, number 2, 1965 June (Item 35)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 12, number 3, 1965 September (Item 36)
    - Issue of The JPS Bookmark, volume 16, number 2, 1968 June (Item 37)
    - "Why the Library Company Should Move", 1960 (Item 38)
    - Auction catalogue, "Western Americana, Pennsylvania German Imprints, Civil War Books and Posters, Maps, Literature, Numismatics", 1964 April 21 (Item 39)
    - Issue of Antiquarian Bookman, 1966 October 17 (Item 40)
    - "Abraham Simon Wolf Rosenbach (1879-1952)", The Jewsish Quarterly Review, volume XLV, 1955 April (Item 41)
    - "A Press for Penn's Pump," The Art Quarterly, 1961 Autumn (Item 42)
    - "Jewish Culture in America: Status and Outlook," Assembly Papers of the 31st General Assembly of the Countil of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, 1962 November 15-18 (Item 43)
    - Address given at the United Hebrew Schools Annual Meeting, Detroit, Michigan, 1963 May 21 (Item 44)
    - "A Press for Penn's Pump," signed gift copy, 1963 (Item 45)
    - Issue of The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress, volume 35, number 3; including an article by Edwin, "The Origins of Early American Printing Shops", 1978 July (Item 46)
    - Special issue of Slavery & Abolition, volume 3, number 1, entitled "Survey of International Archives (Slavery and Abolition)", with The Library Company of Philadelphia and the Historial Society of Pennsylvania, 1982 May (Item 47)
    - "The First Books and Printed Catalogues of the Library Company of Philadelphia", 1954 (Item 48)
    - Book review of John Witherspoon Comes to America. A Documentary Account Based Largely on New Materials, The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, 1954 April (Item 49)
    - "Recent Books on American Jewish History," The Jewish Quarterly Review, 1955 (Item 50)
    - "Recent Books on American Jewish History," The Jewish Quarterly Review, volume XLV, 1955 April (Item 51)
    - Issue of Bulletin of the Special Libraries Council of Philadelphia and Vicinity, volume 22, number 2, 1955 November (Item 52)
    - Issue of Wilson Library Bulletin, volume 30, number 4; including an article by Edwin, "The Early Buying Policy of the Library Company of Philadelphia", 1955 December (Item 53)
    - Panel discussion, "Historical Development of the American Lawyer's Library," Law Library Journal, 1968 (Item 54)
    - Special issue of Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, "Studies on Benjamin Franklin: The Two Hundredth Anniversary of His Birth," volume 99, number 6; including an article by Edwin, "Benjamin Franklin's Stamp Act Cartoon", 1955 December 15 (Item 55)
    - "Benjamin Franklin's Stamp Act Cartoon," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, volume 99, number 6, 1955 December (Item 56)
    - "Franklin and His Friends Choose Their Books," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume LXXX, number 1, 1956 January (Item 57)
    - "Early American Playbills," Shakespeare Quarterly, volume VII, number 2, 1956 Spring (Item 58)
    - "A Key to the Identification of Franklin's Books," Manuscripts, 1956 Summer (Item 59)
    - "A Key to the Identification of Franklin's Books," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume LXXX, number 4, 1956 October (Item 60)
    - "The Romance of James Logan's Books," William and Mary Quarterly, 1956 (Item 61)
    - "The Year After Franklin's Year," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 51, 1957 (Item 62)
    - "The 1706 Charter of the City of Philadelphia," Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, volume 96, number 4, 1952 August (Item 63)
    - "Blake Exhibitions in America," The Book Collector, 1957 (Item 64)
    - Exhibition booklet, "Benjamin Franklin & Winston Churchill: An Exhibition Celebrating the Bicentennial of the University of Pennsylvania Library", 1951 May-June (Item 65)
    - "Colonial American Playbills," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume XCVII, number 1, 1973 January (Item 66)
    - "The Library Company of Philadelphia", 1975 (Item 67)
    - "The Bible in Transition," The Princeton University Library Chronicle, volume XXIV, number 3, 1963 Spring (Item 68)
    - "Some Books of Early New England Provenance in the 1823 Library of Alleghany College," Proceedings of the American Antiquarian Society, 1963 April (Item 69)
    - "Dr. Rosenbach," Manuscripts, volume XV, number 2, 1963 Spring (Item 70)
    - "Wanted: Jewish Intellectuals for Jewish Community Life," The Jewish Digest, volume VIII, number 5, 1963 February (Item 71)
    - "Leadership in the American Jewish Community," The American Jew: A Reappraisal, 1964 (Item 72)
    - "Credo of a Library Conservative," Library Journal, volume 89, number 9, 1964 May 1 (Item 73)
    - "Thoughts on Books and Libraries," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 57, 1963 (Item 74)
    - "A Signed American Binding on the First American Edition of Shakespeare," Shakespeare Quarterly, volume XII, number 2, 1961 Spring (Item 75)
    - "Historical Grist for the Bibliographical Mill," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, volume 25, 1972 (Item 76)
    - "The American Printings of the Definitive Treaty of Peace of 1783 Freed of Obfuscation," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 65 (bound), 1971 (Item 77)
    - "The American Printings of the Definitive Treaty of Peace of 1783 Freed of Obfuscation," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 65 (unbound) (Item 78)
    - Book review of The Library of John Locke, William and Mary Quarterly, 1967 (Item 79)
    - Book review of Guidebook to Jewish Philadelphia, American Jewish Historical Review, volume LV, number 4, 1966 June (Item 80)
    - Issue of Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 54; including a book review by Edwin of Thomas J. Wise Centenary Studies, 1960 (Item 81)
    - Issue of Shakespeare Quarterly, volume VII, number 2; including an article by Edwin, "Early American Playbills" (2 copies), 1956 Spring (Item 82-83)
    - Issue of Rare Books and Manuscripts Librarianship, volume 1, number 1; including an article by Edwin, "Creating an Image", 1986 April (Item 84)
    - "The Library of Edward Lloyd IV of Wye House," Winterthur Portfolio, 5, 1969 (Item 85)
    - "Evidence Indicating the Need for Some Bibliographical Analysis of American-Printed Historical Works," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 63, 1969 (Item 86)
    - "The First Book of Jewish Authorship Printed in America," American Jewish Historical Review, volume LX, number 3, 1971 March (Item 87)
    - "The Year 1745--On-Line," PLA Bulletin, volume 26, number 2, 1971 March (Item 88)
    - "Great American Books Collectors to 1800," Gazette of the Grolier Club, volume 16, 1971 June (Item 89)
    - Exhibition booklet, "James Logan, 1674-1751, Bookman Extraordinary: An Exhibition of Books and Manuscripts from the Library of James Logan, supplemented by his Writings and Documents relating to the History of the Bibliotheca Loganiaca", 1971 (Item 90)
    - "Libraries Don't Get Degrees," New York History, volume LI, 1970 (Item 91)
    - "Wolfe's Copy of Gray's Elegy," The Colophon, volume II, number 3, 1937 (Item 92)
    - "Edward Halle's 'The Vnion of the Two Noble and Illustre Famelies of Lancastre & Yorke' and its Place Among English Americana," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 33, 1939 (Item 93)
    - "Press Corrections in Sixteenth- and Seventeenth-Century Quartos," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 36, 1942 (Item 94)
    - "The Blake-Linnell Accounts in the Library of Yale University," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 37, 1943 (Item 95)
    - "'Stinking' or 'Skinking'? A Bibliographical Study of the 1787 Edinburgh Edition of Burns' Poems," The Library Chronicle, volume XIV, number 1, 1947 April (Item 96)
    - "'If Shadows Be a Picture's Excellence': An Experiment in Critical Bibliography," Publications of the Modern Language Association of America, volume LXIII, number 3, 1948 September (Item 97)
    - "The Textual Importance of Manuscript Commonplace Books of 1620-1660," address given before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1949 January 14 (Item 98)
    - "Fragonard Plates for the Contes et Nouvelles of La Fontaine," Bulletin of the New York Public Library, 1949 March (Item 99)
    - "Benjamin Franklin's Political, Miscellaneous, and Philosophical Pieces, 1779," The Library Chronicle, volume XVI, number 2, 1950 (Item 100)
    - "Gravelot as Designer of Engraved Portrait Frames", 1950 (Item 101)
    - "Horace Wemyss Smith's Recollections of Poe", 1951 (Item 102)
    - Address given before "A Group of Friends of the University of Delaware Library", 1952 April 19 (Item 103)
    - "The Dispersal of the Library of William Byrd of Westover," Proceedings of the American Antiquarian Society, 1958 April (Item 104)
    - "Libraries and Librarians," an address given on the occasion of Drexel University's new Library Center, 1959 April 13 (Item 105)
    - "Four Letters From William Hayley to Emma Hamilton," Manuscripts, volume XI, number 1, 1959 Winter (Item 106)
    - "The Library of a Philadelphia Judge, 1708," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume LXXXIII, number 2, 1959 April (Item 107)
    - "Some Books of Early English Provenance in the Library Company of Philadelphia," The Book Collector, 1960 (Item 108)
    - "Value & Worth of Rare Books," address given at the Antiquarian Booksellers' Association of America, 1961 February 7 (Item 109)
    - "Philadelphia: The Renaissance City," Time, 1982 (Item 110)
    - "Fine Art of Selling Duplicates," The 1968 AB Bookman's Yearbook, twentieth anniversary edition (Item 111)
    - "John Dickinson: Forgotten Patriot," address given at the Dinner of the Friends of John Dickinson Mansion, Inc., 1968 (Item 112)
    - "James Logan's Correspondence with William Reading, Librarian of Sion College," Homage to a Bookman, 1967 (Item 113)
    - "James Logan, Bookman Extraordinary," Proceedings of the Massachusetts Historical Society, 1968 (Item 114)
    - "A Cultural Relic of Colonial America," Wilson Library Bulletin, 1967 February (Item 115)
    - "A 235-Year-Old Library Moves 235,000 Books," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 60, 1966 (Item 116)
    - "Should Libraries Bow or Stretch?," Pennsylvania Library Bulletin, volume 17, number 2, 1961 Fall (Item 117)
    - "The Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's Library: An Unorthodox Jigsaw Puzzle," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 56, 1962 (Item 118)
    - "Ezra Stiles Writes a Hebrew Letter," Studies and Essays in Honor of Abraham A. Newman, 1962 (Item 119)
    - Commencement address given at the College of Jewish Studies, Chicago, 1965 June 20 (Item 120)
    - "The Library of Ralph Assheton: The Book Background of a Colonial Philadelphia Lawyer," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 58, 1964 (Item 121)
    - "The Authorship of the 1774 Address to the King Restudied," William and Mary Quarterly, volume XXII, number 2, 1965 April (Item 122)
    - "A Parcel of Books for the Province in 1700," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume LXXXIX, number 4, 1965 October (Item 123)
    - The History of the Jews in Philadelphia From Colonial Times to the Age of Jackson, first edition, 1956 (Item 124)
    - The History of the Jews in Philadelphia From Colonial Times to the Age of Jackson, bicentennial edition, 1975 (Item 125)
    - "The Jewish Community's Need for Intellectuals", 1962 (Item 126)
    - "Federation and the New Jewish Community," address given at the 64th Annual Meeting of the Jewish Federation, 1964 (Item 127)
    - "Pressures or Priorities," The Jewish Community, volume VIII, number 2, 1953 June (Item 128)
    - Issue of ISIS, volume 50, part 4, number 162; including a book review by Edwin on The Americans; The Colonial Experience, 1959 December (Item 129)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City (sample chapter), 1975 (Item 130)
    - Philadelphia: Portrait of an American City, 1975 (Item 131)
    - Encyclopedia of Library and Information Science, volume 15, "Library Co to Library Re"; including an entry by Edwin on the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1975 (Item 132)
    - Of, By, and For Librarians, second series; including a chapter by Edwin, "Thoughts on Books and Libraries", 1974 (Item 133)
    - "Some Unrecorded American Judaica Printed Before 1851," Essays in American Jewish History, To Commemorate the Tenth Anniversary of the Founding of the American Jewish Archives under the direction of Jacob Rader Marcus, 1958 (Item 134)
    - Classical Traditions in Early America; including a chapter by Edwin, "The Classical Languages in Colonial Philadelphia", 1976 (Item 135)
    - "The Classical Languages of Colonial Philadelphia", 1976 (Item 136)
    - An American Library History Reader: Contributions to Literary Literature; including a chapter by Edwin, "Franklin and His Friends Chose Their Books", 1961 (Item 137)
    - "Frustration and Benjamin Franklin's Medical Books," Science and Society in Early America: Essays in Honor of Whitfield J. Bell, Jr., 1986 (Item 138)
    - "Creating an Image," paper delivered at the Rare Books and Manuscripts Section Preconference, 1986 (Item 139)
    - "The Kern Tom Jones Redivivus," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 84 (multiple copies, shrinkwrapped), 1990 March (Item 140)
    - "How Can We Meet Our Jewish Responsibilities at Home?," address given at the Central Atlantic Regional Conference of the Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, 1953 March 7 (Item 141)
    - "The Origins of Philadelphia's Self-Depreciation, 1820-1920," The Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, volume CIV, number 1, 1980 January (Item 142)
    - "On the Outskirts of Booklore," AB Weekly, 1978 October 2 (Item 143)
    - "The Origins of Early American Printing Shops", 1978 (Item 144)
    - Book review of European Americana: A Chronological Guide to Works Printed in Europe Relating to the Americas, 1493-1776, Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, volume 78 (2 copies), 1984 (Item 145-146)
    - "In the Mainstream of American Book Collecting," The Princeton University Library Chronicle, volume XXXVII, number 2, 1976 Winter (Item 147)
    - "Benjamin Franklin's Way to Wealth," AB Weekly, volume 57, number 20, 1976 May 17 (Item 148)
    - "Black Americana: A New World of Books," AB Weekly, 1976 November 1 (Item 149)
    - "A Flock of Beautiful Birds: The Ornithological Collection of Louise Elkins Sinkler", 1977 (Item 150)
    - "Highlights of American Book Collecting," AB Yearbook, 1976 (Item 151)
    - "More Books from the Library of the Byrds of Westover," American Antiquarian Society, volume 88, part 1, 1978 April (Item 152)
    - "Midwife to a Phoenix: Looking Back Over 25 Years," Bookman's Weekly, 1978 July 3 (Item 153)
  - IIIb. Research, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
    - Bulkeley, Gershom: Photostat of the title page of the Huntington Library copy of People's Right to Election [1689] by Gershom Bulkeley, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook C; 16: To P. Collinson from JL [1737 November 7] (1 item), undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 3, 10: To Collinson from JL [1736 8 June 8-June 12] (2 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 13, 14, 15: To P. Collinson from JL [1736 November 20] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 16, 19: To P. Collinson from JL [1736 December 9-1737 May 20] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 20, 21, 22, 23, and 24: To Peter Collinson from JL [1737 July 25] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 27, 28, and 29: To P. Collinson from JL [1737 August 2-August 20] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 31, 32, 33, 36, and 37: To Peter Collinson from JL [1737 October 10-1737 November 28] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook A; 38, 39, 40, 43, and 44: To P. Collinson from JL [1737 November 30-1738 August 16] (5 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 3, 4: To P. Collinson from JL [1738 October 7-October 20] (2 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 5, 6, 7: To P. Collinson from JL [1738 November 21-1739 April 5] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 9, 10: To P. Collinson from JL [1739 July 25] (1 item), undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 12, 13, 15, 17: To P. Collinson from JL [1739 September 27-1740 April 30] (4 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 18, 19, 20, 21, 22: To P. Collinson from JL [1740 November 7-1741 August 1] (5 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 25, 26, 27: To P. Collinson from JL [1741 August 18-1742 May 28] (6 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook B; 28, 30, 31: To P. Collinson from JL [1742 March 31-1743 September 25] (7 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbooks B; 33 and G; 2, 5, 6: To P. Collinson from JL [1743 November 14-1745 April 12] (7 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook H; 6, 9: To P. Collinson from JL [1745 November 13-1746 February 15] (3 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook G; 6, 7, 8: To P. Collinson from JL [1746 December 8-1747 July 25] (4 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook G; 8, 9, 10: To P. Collinson from JL [1747 September 3-1748 May 24] (5 items), undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letter: To P. Collinson from JL [1749 June 16] (1 item), undated (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Collinson transcriptions, letterbook F: To P. Collinson from JL (1 item), undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin and M. Gwynne, B. Evans, K. Buhler, J. McManaway, and E. C. Bolles (8 items), 1946 November 11-1947 January 24 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin and K. Buhler, G. B. Evans, and R. B. Vowles (10 items), 1947 April 16-April 25 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin, J. G. McManaway and William Parker (18 items), 1948 October 18-1951 February 16 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin and Miss E. Mongan (Bodleian Librarian), H. Mead, Mrs. Wm. Ehrlish, C. T. Keller, Wm. Ringler, G. Goyder, David McKell, M. M. Wise, R. Smith, and F. B. Adams (22 items), 1949 January 5-1952 November 18 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin and Helen S. Sanderson, Agnes M. C. Latham, R. A. Blanchard, A. Baugh, R. Dunlap, and R. G. Collmer (14 items), 1949 January 6-1951 February 10 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Commonplace books: Letters between Edwin and J. M. Osborne, D. M. Vieth, and W. T. Pattison (13 items), 1949 December 5-1951 July 27 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Commonplace books: Letter to Edwin from the Librarian of the Bodleian Library, and typescript copy of “The Textual Importance of Manuscript Commonplace Books of 1620-1660, An Address Before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, January 14, 1949”, 1951 June 6, undated (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Charles Crawford: Letters between Edwin and N. B. Wainwright, C. K. Shipton, Donald Wing, Dennis E. Rhodes, NUC, L. M. Stark, William Jackson, Marjorie Wynne, and L. Leary, typescript of article on Crawford, 1959 August-October (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Charles Crawford: Typescript and copies of manuscript regarding Edwin's reaction to Leary's article on Crawford with a research bibliography appended, circa 1959 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Doctrina Christiana: Research materials, typescript drafts, 1946-1960, circa 1991 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Emblem books: Letter to Edwin from E. P. Newman; copies of American Journal of Numismatics articles from 1875 and 1887; facsimiles of emblem books with notes, 1964 March 23, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Embossed bindings: "American Embossed (Placque) Bindings, 1830-1850," from the collection of Kenneth G. Leach, 1984 (Volume 9)
    - Embossed bindings: Research files, letters, and rubbings (includes photostats, photocopies, and slides), 1990, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - W. H. Emory: Comparisons of several versions of W. H. Emory's "Notes of a Military Reconnaissance" [1848], circa 1970 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - W. H. Emory: Manuscript of article on printing of Emory's notes, eventually used in “Historical Grist for the Bibliographical Mill”; letter to Edwin from Andrea J. Tucker, circa 1970, 1982 November 1 (Box 26, Folder 4)